Finding Aid for Mabel E. Rugen Papers 1921-1989
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Associations
  - Michigan Association for Health, Physical Education and Recreation 1960-1966 (Box 13)
  - Michigan Council on Family Relations 1957-1968 (Box 13)
  - Michigan Dept. of Public Health 1958-1968 (Box 13)
  - Michigan Dept. of Public Instruction, Division of Vocational Education Health Education Curriculum Committee 1961-1964 (Box 13)
  - Michigan Education Association 1948-1951 (Box 13)
  - Michigan Health Council 1949-1969 (Box 13)
  - Michigan League, Board of Governors 1945-1961 (Box 13)
  - Michigan Physical Education Association 1935-1951 (Box 13)
  - Michigan Public Health Association 1967-1973 (Box 13)
  - Michigan School Health Association 1943-1980 (Box 13)
  - Mid-West Association of College Teachers of Physical Education for Women 1948-1953 (Box 13)
  - Mid-West Physical Education Association 1933-1934 (Box 13)
  - National Conference on Undergraduate Preparation for Health Education, Physical Education and Recreation 1948 (Box 13)
  - Society of Public Health Educators (SOPHE)
    - Correspondence
      - 1952-1973, 3 folders (Box 13)
      - Beryl Roberts Prize 1970-1974 (Box 13)
    - Board of Directors
      - Minutes 1958-1960 (Box 14)
      - Reports 1959-1960 (Box 14)
    - Great Lakes Chapter 1969-1976 (Box 14)
  - Washtenaw County Nursing Council
    - Minutes 1950-1956 (Box 14)
  - Washtenaw Tuberculosis and Health Association 1971-1973 (Box 14)
  - Wayne County Medical Society 1961 (Box 14)
  - Women of the University Faculty (Univ. of Mich.) 1946-1951 (Box 14)
  - YMCA Community Leadership Development Workshop 1963-1966 (Box 14)
- Topical File
  Lastly, a Topical File (1.75 linear ft.; 1930-1969) includes material documenting Rugen's various professional interests. Papers documenting Rugen's involvement in curriculum changes and national standardization for the Master of Public Health degree during the 1960s reflect her continuing contributions to the field of public health education. These papers, mostly correspondence and reports, are arranged by originating agency.
  - Educational Testing Service 1953 (Box 14)
  - Field Hockey, Ann Arbor Hockey Club 1930s (Box 14)
  - Field Work 1939 (Box 14)
  - Health Education Projects, Tecumseh Study 1958 (Box 14)
  - Health Knowledge Tests 1930s (Box 14)
  - International Conference on Health and Health Education June 30-July 7, 1962 (Box 14)
  - International Union for Health Education of the Public 1956-1958 (Box 14)
  - Kentucky Dept of Health
    - District Meetings 1965 (Box 14)
    - Health Education Staff Meeting 1964 (Box 14)
  - Progressive Health Education, Field Study 1937 (Box 14)
  - Public Health Nursing 1955-1956 (Box 14)
  - Radio Scripts 1942-1945 (Box 14)
  - Rural School Health Education Activities 1938 (Box 14)
  - University of Michigan
    - Extension Division 1967 (Box 14)
    - Extension Service, Hillsdale, MI 1934-1935 (Box 14)
    - Health Information Service Committee 1955 (Box 14)
  - Professional Education in Public Health
    - General: Papers and reports 1950-1968 (Box 15)
    - American Academy of Physical Education 1966 (Box 15)
    - American Public Health Association
      - Committee on Professional Education 1947-1967, 7 folders (Box 15)
      - Sub-committee on Health Education 1966 (Box 15)
      - Reports 1963-1967 (Box 15)
    - Association of Schools of Public Health 1950s-1960s (Box 15)
    - Background Reports for Review of Health Education Programs of Study 1966-1967 (Box 15)
    - Health Education Consultants Meeting 1963 (Box 15)
    - Health Education Research Council 1969-1974 (Box 15)
    - Professors of Public Health Education / Association of Schools of Public Health 1954-1957 (Box 15)
    - Professors of Public Health Education
      - Conference April 8-10, 1961 (Box 15)
      - Conference April 18-19, 1962 (Box 15)
    - Public Health Education Requirements 1949 (Box 15)
    - Requirements for the Master of Public Health 1956-1963 (Box 15)
    - Society of Public Health Educators (SOPHE) 1965-1967, 3 folders (Box 15)
    - U.S. Dept. of Health, Education and Welfare 1961 (Box 15)